MUSTAFA DURMUŞ

Computer Engineer

P Istanbul | \$\secup +90 0530 891 98 04 | ™ mustafa-durmuss@outlook.com





Summary___

Hello, I am Mustafa. I like working on projects that solve real world problems using AI. I have been interested in artificial intelligence, machine learning and natural language processing since 2018. I prefer to continue progressing in that and related business roles.

Work Experience_____

NLP Engineer Istanbul/Turkey

ALBERT HEALTH Dec 2020 – Present

• I am trying to improve our NLU products and create new NLP applications. My responsibilities include transforming natural language data into useful features using NLP techniques to feed classification algorithms.

Robotics Developer Istanbul/Turkey

HUMMINGDRONE AVIATION & AEROSPACE

Jul 2019 - Dec 2020

• I was in Robotics Development Team. The team deeply focused on making data-driven drones, using approaches like: Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Visual SLAM, Amazon Web Services and open-source robotics technologies.

Internship Istanbul/Turkey

PROJ-E SOFTWARE Jul 2017 – Aug 2017

 I did my first compulsory internship in this company that specializes in web-based software and strategy development. It was my first time that I used HTML, CSS, XML and similar applications severely.

Internship Istanbul/ Turkey

TURKEY FOUNDATIONS BANK

Sep 2012 - Jun 2013

• In my high school long-term internship, I was generally interested in topics on Information Technology, Hardware, Networking.

Volunteer Projects_____

Deep Learning Turkey

Istanbul/Turkey

Jul 2019- Oct 2019

• I participated in the "Hands on AI Project" that organized by Deep Learning Turkey community and continued for 4 months. I am in the team who works on the project of Real Time Object Detection in Occupational Safety. We used approaches and applications like: YOLOV3, Amazon Web Services, RabbitMQ, RaspberryPi.

Education_____

Karabuk University Karabuk/Turkey

Master of Science - Computer Engineering Sep 2020 - Present

Vytautas Magnus University Kaunas/Lithuania

Exchange Programme Aug 2017 – Jan 2018

• I have participated Erasmus programme in Lithuania for 5 months.

Karabuk University Karabuk/Turkey

Bachelor of Science - Computer Engineering | GPA of 3.47/4.00

2014 - 2019

- I have taken theoretical and practical valuable lessons starting from programming in many areas of computer engineering and participated in various activities. I did my compulsory internship with one of my university teachers and together we developed a project using the Django framework. I have worked on my own thesis for 9 months during my senioryear.
- I developed a natural language processing model called image captioning which generates textual description of the given images for bachelor's degree final project. I used convolutional and recurrent neural nets in a same problem.

Skills

- Programming (Python, Bash)
- > AI (Machine Learning, NLP, Reinforcement Learning, Computer Vision)
- Linux (Ubuntu)
- Cloud (Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform)
- Robotics (ROS, Gazebo, Rviz)
- Version Control (Git, Github, Bitbucket)

References_____

(1) Prof. Dr. Oğuz FINDIK

Karabuk University Computer Engineering Department e-mail: oguzfindik@karabuk.edu.tr

(2) Orkun AŞA

Co-Founder – Computer Engineer at Hummingdrone e-mail: orkun@hummingdrone.co